web assembly write applications for the web and languages other than javascript
Web 程序集为Web 和除 javascript 以外的其他语言编写应用程序
imagine a world where you could build software with c plus plus rust python go
想象一个世界，您可以使用 c plus plus rust python go
or even cobalt then deliver that software to the end user in a web
甚至钴构建软件，然后在 Web 浏览器中将该软件交付给最终用户，
browser without any installation and near native performance that world
无需任何安装且接近本机性能 世界
became a reality in december 2019 when webassembly became an official w3c
在 2019 年 12 月成为现实，当时 webassembly 成为官方 w3c
standard it includes a low-level language similar
标准，它包括一种类似于汇编的低级语言
to assembly that can be represented with text
，可以用文本表示，
then converted to a binary format that runs on all modern browsers
然后转换为可在所有现代浏览器上运行的二进制格式，
however you won't actually write this code directly but rather use it as a
但你实际上不会写这个直接编写代码，而是将其用作
compilation target for programs written in other languages
以其他语言编写的程序的编译目标，
for example you might build a game with unity and c-sharp
例如，您可以使用unity 和 c-sharp 构建游戏，
then compile it to webassembly where it can be delivered in the browser
然后将其编译为 webassembly，然后可以在浏览器中交付
now it's important to note that it's not intended to replace javascript
它现在重要的是要注意它不是打算替换
in fact the two work well together side by side figma for example
javascript 实际上两者并肩工作很好figma 例如
uses react.js for its outer ui then on the inside you have a high performance c
使用 react.js 作为其外部 ui 然后在内部，您拥有一个高性能的 c
plus plus design tool that feels just as fast as native software
plus plus 设计工具，感觉与
as a developer there are many different ways you can build a webassembly app
开发人员的本地软件一样快 有许多不同的方法可以构建一个 webassembly 应用程序
with many more under development one of the most popular tools is mscriptin
，还有更多正在开发中的最流行的工具之一是 mscriptin
which can convert a c or c plus plus program to webassembly as
，它可以 将 c或 c plus plus 程序转换为 webassembly，
it did by bringing autocad to the web which is a 30 year old codebase
就像通过将 autocad 引入网络一样，这是一个有 30 年历史的代码库
no way one of the best ways to get started is with assembly script which is
，最好的入门方法之一是使用汇编脚本，它是
a language that looks like typescript but compiles to webassembly we can
一种看起来像 typescript但编译为的语言 webassembly 我们可以
easily start a new assembly script project
using node.js and npm then we'll write our first webassembly module
使用 node.js 和 npm 轻松启动一个新的汇编脚本项目，然后我们将在 index ts 文件中编写我们的第一个 webassembly 模块
in the index ts file unlike javascript a dynamic interpreted language
，这与 javascript 不同的是动态解释语言
webassembly is a static compiled language with strict type guarantees
webassembly 是一种具有严格类型保证的静态编译语言，
for example our code can't use the any type when it comes to numbers
例如我们的代码 不能使用任何类型的数字
we need to specify a 32-bit integer or a 64-bit floating point
我们需要指定一个 32 位整数或64 位
in addition we can't use dynamic objects instead we use maps where we can
浮点此外我们不能使用动态对象 相反，我们使用映射，
strongly type the key value pairs once we're happy with our code we can then
一旦我们对代码感到满意，我们就可以强输入键值对，然后我们可以将其
compile it down to a binary which is a file that ends in
编译成二进制文件，该文件是以 wasm 结尾的文件，
wasm we can now run this binary in the browser open an html page
我们现在可以在浏览器中运行这个二进制文件打开一个 html 页面
and then use the webassembly api to instantiate streaming
，然后使用 webassembly api实例化流，
simply fetch the binary and when the promise resolves do something with it
只需获取二进制文件，当promise 解决时，用它做一些事情，
this has been webassembly in 100 seconds if you want to see a more in-depth video
如果你想看到关于这个主题的更深入的视频
on this topic please let me know in the comments and
，请在 100 秒内让我知道 评论并
make sure to subscribe and hit the like button
确保订阅并点击喜欢按钮
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢观看，我会在下一个看到你